Imayan Gowthaman

Software Development Specialist

+1 312-785-0828 gowtham.ongc@gmail.com

Summary

A passionate full spectrum Software developer/Integrator with years of experience in designing, developing and deploying software solutions for Manufacturing, Insurance & SaaS companies. I'm an advocate for functional, Integration, Reporting and user-centered products which has an impact on people's life solving a need. I have a strong notion that a good product is a concoction of design and technology.

Education

Master of Science, Computer Science

DePaul University, Chicago - Jun 2021 (Expected)

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer, Accenture

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

Designed and Developed Web Portal which is focused on integrating the customer interaction with business users.

Creation of Automation Test cases for unit testing.

Involved in planning and designing of an automation system to migrate millions of legacy data into current systems.

Senior Developer, HCL Corporation

April 2016- May 2018

Worked on the Development of Output Delivery Module which focuses on verifying and packaging the info, for delivering it to customers. Creation of a rule engine using WCF Services to process data (Source data in XML, JSON, Ascii file format).

Software Engineer, Tech Mahindra

August 2013 - April 2016

Involved in Design and development of Calculation Engine for Sales Module. Involved in development and integration of an HTML 5 Application to geolocate the nearby Customer premises within the specified range.

Involved in Custom Report Generation for Forecasting and displaying sale charts. Involved in Design and Integration of MSCRM Mobile App with desktop Application.

App Developer, DePaul University

Feb 2019-Present

Involved in planning, designing and development of Student interaction App in both IOS and Android.

Key Skills

MSCRM Specialist

C++ Optimization

SSIS Integrator

Reporting

UI Designer

Testing Automation

Usability Testing

Web Development using angular/Angular CLI

Object Oriented Development

Software Dev Life Cycle

Agile Methodology

Tools

IntelliJ, Visual Studio, SSRS,SSIS, Azure.

Databases

SQL Server 2005/2008, Oracle SQL Developer

Development

C++,C#,Java,Angular,SQL,Python,R, HTML, CSS, Javascript

Activities

Student Member at the DePaul XD Roundtable

College Projects

Optimizing Particle Engine using C++